Downloaded @ subs4free.club
Open your eyes.
This is where our magic comes from?
Mm-hmm.
This candle holds the miracle
given to our family.
How did we get a miracle?
Long ago...
when my three babies had just been born...
your abuelo Pedro and
I were forced to flee our home.
And though many joined us...
hoping to find a new home...
we could not escape the dangers...
and your abuelo was lost.
But in our darkest moment...
we were given a miracle.
The candle became a magical flame
that could never go out.
And it blessed us with a refuge
in which to live.
A place of wonder.
An encanto.
The miracle grew.
And our house...
our casita itself...
came alive to shelter us.
When my children came of age...
the miracle blessed each
with a magic Gift to help us.
And when their children came of age...
They got magic, too.
That's right!
And together, our family's Gifts...
have made our new home a paradise.
Tonight, this candle will give you your Gift,
mi vida.
Strengthen our community,
strengthen our home.
Make your family proud.
Make my family proud.
Yes, yes, casita, we're going!
What do you think my Gift will be?
You are a wonder, Mirabel Madrigal.
Whatever Gift awaits...
will be just as special as you.
Make your family proud.
Morning, Abuelo!
Hey! When's the magic Gift happen?
My cousin's ceremony is tonight.
What's his Gift?
We're gonna find out!
What's your Gift?
Who's asking?
Us!
Well, "us," I can't just talk about myself.
I'm only part of the amazing Madrigals.
Who's all the amazing Madrigals?
Ah, you're not gonna leave me alone, are you?
Casita, help me out.
Drawers!
Floors!
Doors!
Let's go!
This is our home
We've got every generation
So full of music
A rhythm of its own design
This is my family
A perfect constellation
So many stars
And everybody gets to shine
Whoa
But let's be clear
Abuela runs this show
Whoa
She led us here so many years ago
And every year our family blessings grow
There's just a lot
You simply got to know so
Welcome to the family Madrigal
The home of the family Madrigal
We're on our way
Where all the people are fantastical
And magical
I'm part of the family Madrigal
- Oh, my gosh! It's them!
- What are the Gifts?
- I can't remember all the Gifts!
- But I don't know who is who.
All right, all right, relax!
- It is physically impossible to relax!
- Tell us everything!
- What are your powers?
- Just tell us what everyone can do!
And that's why coffee's for grown-ups.
My tía Pepa
Her mood affects the weather
When she's unhappy
Well, the temperature gets weird
My tío Bruno
We don't talk about Bruno!
They say he saw the future
One day he disappeared
Oh
And that's my mom Julieta, here's her deal
Whoa
The truth is she can heal you with a meal
Her recipes are remedies for real
If you're impressed
Imagine how I feel
Mom!
Welcome to the family Madrigal
The home of the family Madrigal
Hey, coming through!
I know it sounds a bit fantastical
And magical
But I'm part of the family Madrigal
-Two guys fell in love with family Madrigal
-With family Madrigal
-And now they're part of the family Madrigal
-The family Madrigal
See, yeah, Tío Félix married Pepa
And my dad married Julieta
-That's how Abuela became an abuela Madrigal
-Abuela Madrigal
Let's go Let's go
We swear to always
Help those around us
And earn the miracle
That somehow found us
The town keeps growing
The world keeps turning
But work and dedication
Will keep the miracle burning
And each new generation
Must keep the miracle burning
Wait, who's the sister and who's the cousin?
There are so many people!
How do you keep them all straight?
Okay, okay, okay.
So many kids in our house
So, let's turn the sound up
You know why?
I think it's time for a Grandkid Round-up!
Grandkid Round-up
Cousin Dolores can hear a pin drop
Camilo shapeshifts
Antonio gets his Gift today
-My older sisters Isabela and Luisa
-Isabela and Luisa
One strong, one graceful
Perfect in every way
-Isabela
-Grows a flower and the town goes wild
Isabela
She's the perfect golden child
Luisa, Luisa
And Luisa's super strong
The beauty and the brawn do no wrong
- Let's get ready!
- Coming, Abuela!
That's life in the family Madrigal
Now you know the family Madrigal
Where all the people are fantastical
And magical
That's who we are in the family Madrigal
Adiós
But what's your Gift?
Well, I gotta go
The life of a Madrigal
But now you all know the family Madrigal
I never meant this to get autobiographical
It was just to review the family Madrigal
Let's go
- But what about Mirabel?
- It starts with Abuela
And then Tía Pepa
She handles the weather
But what about Mirabel?
My mom Julieta can make you feel better
With just one arepa
- But what about Mirabel?
- My dad Agustín
Well he's accident-prone
But he means well
But what about Mirabel?
Hey you said you wanna know what
Everyone does, I got sisters and cousins and
Mirabel
My primo Camilo won't stop
Until he makes you smile today
My cousin Dolores can hear
This whole chorus a mile away
Look
It's Mr. Mariano
Hey you can marry my sister if you wanna
Between you and me
She's kind of a prima donna
Oh, I've said too much
And thank you but I really gotta go
-My family's amazing
-Mirabel
-And I'm in my family so
Well
Mirabel!
What are you doing?
They were just asking about the family and...
She was about to tell us
about her super awesome Gift!
Oh, Mirabel didn't get one.
You didn't get a Gift?
Mirabel! Delivery!
I gave you the special since
you're the only Madrigal kid with no Gift.
I call it the "Not Special Special"
since you have no Gift.
Thanks.
Oh, and tell Antonio good luck.
The last Gift ceremony was a bummer.
Last one being yours that did not work.
If I was you, I'd be really sad.
Well, my little friend, I am not.
Because the truth is, Gift or no Gift...
I am just as special
as the rest of my family.
Who wants more pink?
All right, guys, where do I drop the wagon?
Maybe your Gift is being in denial.
I made a rainbow!
Get the chairs out of the way.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
Dolores, can you hear
if anyone is gonna be late?
Lift it higher.
Higher.
- Hey, nice job over there.
- Yeah, yeah.
Camilo, we need another José!
José!
Luisa, the piano goes upstairs!
I'm on it!
Careful, sis!
My baby's night has to be perfect,
and it's not perfect.
And people are going to be coming.
And nothing's ready.
The flowers!
Did someone say flowers?
Isabela!
Our angel, our angel!
Please don't clap.
- Thank you.
- Oh, it's nothing.
A little sisterly advice...
if you weren't always trying too hard,
you wouldn't be in the way.
Actually, Isa, this is called helping.
And I'm not in the way.
You are.
Excuse me.
Mi vida, you okay?
You don't have to overdo it.
I know, Mamá.
I just wanna do my part
like the rest of the family.
She's right, amor.
First Gift ceremony since yours.
A lot of emotions.
- Bee stings!
- And I've been there.
When me and your tío Félix
married into the family...
outsiders who had no Gift,
never, ever would...
surrounded by the exceptional,
it was easy to feel...
un-ceptional.
Okay, Papi.
- I'm just saying, I get it.
- Eat.
Mi amor, if you ever wanna talk...
I gotta put out the stuff.
The house isn't gonna decorate itself.
Sorry, you could. You look great.
- Corazón, remember!
- Yeah, remember!
- You have nothing to prove!
- You guys can set up over here.
- Clean your rooms!
I don't care how big they are.
Has anybody seen my tiple?
One hour!
No, no, no!
Maybe you should leave the decorations
to someone else?
No, I actually made these
as a surprise for you.
Mirabel, I know you want to help.
But tonight must go perfectly.
The whole town relies on our family,
on our Gifts.
So, the best way for some of us to help
is to step aside.
Let the rest of the family
do what they do best.
Okay?
Mm-hmm.
- Pepa! You have a cloud!
- I know, Mamá.
But now I can't find Antonio.
What do you want from me?
Mamá, be nice to Mirabel, okay?
You know tonight will be hard for her.
If the Gift ceremony doesn't go well
this time...
tonight will be hard for us all.
Antonio!
Everyone's looking for you.
This present will self-destruct
if you don't take it...
in three...
two...
one...
Nervous?
You have nothing to worry about.
You're gonna get your Gift
and open that door...
and it's gonna be the coolest ever.
I know it.
What if it doesn't work?
Well, in that impossible scenario...
you'd stay here in the nursery with me.
Forever.
And I'd get you all to myself.
I wish you could have a door.
You know what?
You don't have to worry about me...
'cause I have an amazing family...
and an amazing house.
And an amazing you.
And seeing you get your special Gift
and your door...
that's gonna make me
way more happy than anything.
But, alas, I am gonna miss
having the world's best roomie.
I know you're an animal guy...
and I made this so,
when you move into your cool, new room...
you always have something to snuggle with.
All right, hombrecito, you ready?
Sorry, I got to get one more squeeze.
Okay, okay, we're going!
Here you go!
Cecilia, up top!
There you are.
Look at you! All grown up.
Pepi, amor, you're gonna get him all wet.
You are making your papa proud.
I don't sound like that.
Abuela says it's time.
We'll be waiting at your door.
Okay, okay.
All right, I'm done!
Fifty years ago...
in our darkest moment...
this candle blessed us with a miracle.
And the greatest honor of our family...
has been to use our blessings
to serve this beloved community.
Tonight, we come together once more...
as another steps into the light...
to make us proud.
I can't.
I need you.
Come on, let's get you to your door.
Will you use your Gift
to honor our miracle?
Will you serve this community...
and strengthen our home?
I understand you.
Of course they can come!
We have a new Gift!
It's bigger on the inside?
Antonio!
You wanna go where?
- That was great!
- Okay! All right!
That was amazing.
I knew you could do it!
A Gift just as special as you.
We need a picture!
Everyone! Come, come, come!
It's a great night! It's a perfect night!
Everyone, together!
La Familia Madrigal!
Don't be upset or mad at all
Don't feel regret or sad at all
Hey, I'm still a part
of the family Madrigal
And I'm fine I am totally fine
I will stand on the side as you shine
I'm not fine I'm not fine
I can't move the mountains
I can't make flowers bloom
I can't take another night up in my room
Waiting on a miracle
I can't heal what's broken
Can't control the morning rain or a hurricane
Can't keep down the unspoken invisible pain
Always waiting on a miracle
A miracle
Always walking alone
Always wanting for more
Like I'm still at that door
Longing to shine
Like all of you shine
All I need is a change
All I need is a chance
All I know is I can't stay on the side
Open your eyes
Open your eyes Open your eyes
I would move the mountains
Make new trees and flowers grow
Someone please just let me know where do I go
I am waiting on a miracle
A miracle
I would heal what's broken
Show this family something new
Who I am inside
So what can I do?
I'm sick of waiting on a miracle
So here I go
I am ready Come on, I'm ready
I've been patient and steadfast and steady
Bless me now
As you blessed us all those years ago
When you gave us a miracle
Am I too late for a miracle?
Casita?
Come on, Abuela!
The house is in danger!
The tiles were falling,
and there were cracks everywhere.
And the candle almost went out.
Show me.
What?
No, that's...
The cracks were there.
They were everywhere.
The house was in trouble, the candle was...
Abuela, I promise...
That's enough.
There is nothing wrong
with La Casa Madrigal.
The magic is strong.
And so are the drinks.
Please! Music!
If it was all in my head,
how did I cut my hand?
I would never ruin Antonio's night.
Is that really what you think?
What I think
is that today was very hard for you.
That's...
I was looking out for the family.
And I might not be super strong like Luisa...
or effortlessly perfect
like señorita perfecta Isabela...
who's never even had a bad hair day, but...
whatever.
I wish you could see yourself the way I do.
You are perfect just like this.
You're just as special
as anyone else in this family.
You just healed my hand
with an arepa con queso.
I healed your hand
with my love for my daughter...
with her wonderful brain...
- and big heart, cool glasses...
- Stop!
Mamá!
I know what I saw.
Mira, my brother Bruno
lost his way in this family.
I don't want the same for you.
Get some sleep.
You'll feel better tomorrow.
Pedro.
I need you.
Cracks in our casita.
If our family knew
how vulnerable we truly are...
If our miracle is dying...
We cannot lose our home again.
Why is this happening?
Open my eyes.
If the answer is here, help me find it.
Help me protect our family.
Help me save our miracle.
I will save the miracle.
Wait. How do I save a miracle?
I figure out what's happening
to the miracle.
Oh, I have no idea.
But there is one person in this family
who hears everything about everything.
So, if anyone would know what's wrong
with the magic...
Hey!
...it's her.
Dolores, hey.
You know, out of all my older cousins,
you're, like, my favorite cousin...
so I feel like I can talk to you
about anything...
ergo you can talk to me about anything.
Like the problem with the magic last night
that no one seemed to worry about...
but maybe you heard about
that maybe I should know about.
Camilo! Stop pretending you're Dolores
so you can have seconds.
Worth a shot.
The only one worried about the magic
is you...
and the rats talking in the walls.
And Luisa, I heard her eye twitching
all night.
There we go.
Everyone, to the table!
Let's go, let's go.
- Luisa.
- Family.
We are all thankful
for Antonio's wonderful new Gift.
I told them to warm up your seat.
Thank you, Toñito.
I'm sure today we'll find a way
to put your blessings to good use.
Luisa, Dolores says
you're totally freaking out.
Any chance you maybe know something
about last night with the magic...
- You do!
- Mirabel!
- If you can't pay attention, I will help you.
- Actually...
Casita!
As I was saying...
we must never take our miracle for granted...
so today we will work twice as hard.
- Mm-hmm. I will help Luisa.
- Stop.
First, an announcement.
I've spoken to the Guzmáns
about Mariano's proposal to Isabela.
Dolores, do we have a date?
Tonight. He wants five babies.
Wonderful!
Such a fine young man
with our perfect Isabela...
will bring a new generation
of magical blessings...
and make both of our families stronger.
Okay. Our community is counting on us.
La Familia Madrigal!
Luisa, hey.
What?
- Sorry.
- What is your problem?
Hey! Luisa, hold up!
- Luisa, can you re-route the river?
- Will do.
- Luisa, the donkeys got out again.
- On it.
Luisa!
Wait a second!
You gotta tell me about the magic.
What's going on?
What are you hiding?
Nothing. Just got a lot of chores,
so maybe you should just go home.
Luisa, my house is leaning to the...
Dolores said your eye was twitching,
and it never twitches.
Something's making you nervous.
Hey, move.
You're gonna make me drop a donkey.
Luisa, will you just...
- Just tell me what it is.
- There's nothing to tell.
You're obviously worried
about something.
Luisa, if you know
what's hurting the magic...
and it gets worse,
'cause you won't tell me what's wrong...
Nothing's wrong!
Wow, sorry.
That snuck out there.
What I meant was...
Why would anything be wrong?
I'm totally fine.
The magic's fine.
Luisa's fine.
I'm totally not nervous.
Your eye is doing the thing...
I'm the strong one
I'm not nervous
I'm as tough as the crust of the Earth is
Okay.
I move mountains I move churches
And I glow 'cause I know what my worth is
Of course, I mean...
Hey, where are you going?
I don't ask how hard the work is
Got a rough, indestructible surface
Diamonds and platinum
I find 'em I flatten 'em
I take what I'm handed
I break what's demanded
But under the surface, I feel berserk
As a tightrope walker in a three-ring circus
Under the surface
Was Hercules ever like
"Yo, I don't wanna fight Cerberus"
Under the surface
I'm pretty sure I'm worthless
If I can't be of service
A flaw or a crack
The straw in the stack
That breaks the camel's back
What breaks the camel's back?
It's pressure like a drip, drip, drip
That'll never stop
Whoa
Pressure that'll tip, tip, tip
Till you just go pop
Whoa
Give it to your sister
Your sister's older
Give her all the heavy things
We can't shoulder
Who am I if I can't run with the ball?
If I fall to pressure like a grip, grip, grip
And it won't let go
Whoa
Pressure like a tick, tick, tick
Till it's ready to blow
Whoa
Give it to your sister
Your sister's stronger
See if she can hang on a little longer
Who am I if I can't carry it all?
If I falter
Under the surface
I hide my nerves and it worsens
I worry something is gonna hurt us
Under the surface
The ship doesn't swerve
As it heard how big the iceberg is
Under the surface
I think about my purpose
Can I somehow preserve this?
Line up the dominos
A light wind blows
You try to stop it topplin'
But on and on it goes But wait
If I could shake
The crushing weight of expectations
Would that free some room up for joy
Or relaxation?
Or a simple pleasure
Instead we measure
This growing pressure keeps growing
Keep going 'cause all we know is
Pressure like a drip, drip, drip
That'll never stop
Whoa
Pressure that'll tip, tip, tip
Till you just go pop
Whoa
Give it to your sister
It doesn't hurt
And see if she can handle every family burden
Watch as she buckles
And bends but never breaks
No mistakes
Just pressure like a grip, grip, grip
And it won't let go
Whoa
Pressure like a tick, tick, tick
Till it's ready to blow
Whoa
Give it to your sister and never wonder
If the same pressure
Would have pulled you under
Who am I if I don't have what it takes?
No cracks No breaks
No mistakes No pressure
I think you're carrying way too much...
Maybe I overdo it.
Yep.
There is something you should know.
Last night, when you saw the cracks...
I felt... weak.
What?
- Luisa! The donkeys!
- On it!
Wait, wait, wait.
What do you mean?
What do you think's hurting the magic?
Don't know, but I heard the grown-ups once.
Before Tío Bruno left...
he had, like, some terrible vision about it.
Tío Bruno?
What was in his vision?
No one knows.
They never found it.
But if something's wrong with the magic,
start with Bruno's tower.
Find that vision.
Wait! How do you find a vision?
What am I even looking for?
If you find it, you'll know.
But be careful.
That place is off limits for a reason.
Such a perfect match.
So perfect.
And so good for the encanto.
Casita.
Can you turn off the sand?
You can't help in here?
I'll be fine.
I need to do this.
For you, for Abuela...
maybe a little for me.
"Find the vision, save the..."
Oh, hello.
Lot of stairs...
but at least I'll have a friend.
No. He flew away immediately.
All right.
Welcome to the family Madrigal
There's so many stairs in the casa Madrigal
You think there would be another way to
Get so high 'cause we're magic, but no
Magical how many stairs fit in here!
Bruno, your room is the worst!
Come on...
Okay, I can do this.
Quitter!
Empty.
What's hurting the magic?
Me.
Where are you coming from in such a hurry?
I'm sorry I was...
What is in your hair?
My Gift!
- I'm losing my Gift!
- What?
Mirabel and I were having
this little talk about me carrying too much.
So, I tried not to carry so much,
but I realized it was putting me behind.
And I knew I was gonna let everyone down.
And I felt really bad,
so I was grabbing all the donkeys...
but then when I went to throw
the donkeys in the barn, they were...
heavy!
What did you do?
What did you say to her?
Nothing. I don't...
Mirabel, I have to go get the Guzmáns
for Isabela's engagement.
Stay away from Luisa
until I can talk to her.
Tonight, we can't have any more problems.
And whatever you're doing,
stop doing it.
Why am I in your vision, Bruno?
Tía! Jeez.
Sorry, I didn't mean to...
Shoo, shoo, shoo!
I just wanted to get
the last of Toñito's things...
and then I heard the name we do not speak.
Great. Now I'm thundering,
and that thunder will lead to a drizzle...
and a drizzle will lead to a sprinkle...
Clear skies, clear skies.
Clear skies.
Tía Pepa? If...
If he had a vision about someone,
what would it mean for them?
We don't talk about Bruno.
I know. It's just hypothetically,
if he saw you...
Mirabel, please,
we need to get ready for the Guzmáns.
I just wanna know if it was generally
positive or, like, less positive...
- It was a nightmare!
- Félix!
Hey, she needs to know, Pepi,
she needs to know.
We don't talk about Bruno.
He would see something terrible.
And then...
Boom! It would happen.
We don't talk about Bruno.
What if you didn't understand what he saw?
Then you better figure it out,
because it was coming for you.
We don't talk about Bruno-no-no-no
We don't talk about Bruno
-But it was my wedding day
-It was our wedding day
We were getting ready
And there wasn't a cloud in the sky
No clouds allowed in the sky
Bruno walks in
With a mischievous grin
Thunder
You're telling the story or am I?
I'm sorry, mi vida Go on
Bruno says it looks like rain
Why did he tell her?
In doing so, he floods my brain
Abuela gets the umbrella
Married in a hurricane
What a joyous day But anyway
We don't talk about Bruno-no-no-no
We don't talk about Bruno
Hey
Grew to live in fear of
Bruno stuttering or stumbling
I can always hear him sort of muttering
And mumbling
I associate him with
The sound of falling sand
It's a heavy lift with a Gift so humbling
Always left Abuela and the family fumbling
Grappling with prophecies
They couldn't understand
Do you understand?
Seven-foot frame
Rats along his back
When he calls your name
It all fades to black
Yeah, he sees your dreams
And feasts on your screams
We don't talk about Bruno-no-no-no
We don't talk about Bruno
He told me my fish would die
The next day dead
No, no
He told me I'd grow a gut
And just like he said
-No, no
-He said that all my hair would disappear
Now look at my head
No, no
Your fate is sealed
When your prophecy is read
He told me
That the life of my dreams
Would be promised and someday be mine
He told me that my power would grow
Like the grapes that thrive on the vine
Mariano's on his way
He told me that the man of my dreams
Would be just out of reach
Betrothed to another
-It's like I hear him now
-Hey, sis
I want not a sound out of you
I can hear him now
Um, Bruno Yeah, about that Bruno
I really need to know about Bruno
Give me the truth and the whole truth, Bruno
Isabela, your boyfriend's here!
Time for dinner
-It was my wedding day
-It was our wedding day
-And there wasn't a cloud in the sky
-No clouds allowed in the sky
He told me that my power would grow
-Thunder
-You're telling the story or am I?
Mariano's on his way
-Bruno says it looks like rain
-Why did he tell her?
-In doing so, he floods my brain
-Abuela gets the umbrella
Married in a hurricane
He's here
Don't talk about Bruno-no
Why did I talk about Bruno?
Not a word about Bruno
I never should have brought up Bruno
Miraboo!
Got your party pants on? 'Cause I...
I broke into Bruno's tower.
I found his last vision.
The family's in trouble.
The magic is dying. The house is breaking,
Luisa's gift is fading.
And I think it's all because of me?
Pá?
We say nothing.
Abuela wants tonight to be perfect.
Until the Guzmáns leave,
you did not break into Bruno's tower.
The magic is not dying.
The house is not breaking.
Luisa's gift is not fading.
No one will know.
Just act normal.
No one has to know.
I know.
She's gonna tell everyone.
Time to eat!
The Guzmáns and the Madrigals together
will be so good for the encanto.
Yes. Then, let's hope
tonight is not a horrible disaster.
To a perfect night!
Avocado?
Camilo. Fix your face.
Water?
Mirabel.
The cream, please?
Pá, the cream?
...Bruno's vision.
Pepa, the cloud.
Clear skies, clear skies, clear skies.
Bruno's vision.
Mirabel?
Everything okay?
Everything is great.
She's just excited.
For you to propose.
Which you should do!
- Yes.
- As fast as you can.
I was actually gonna...
You were actually gonna.
Great!
Well, since everyone here has a talent...
my Mariano wanted to
begin with a song!
Luisa, could you bring over the piano?
Okay.
It's actually family tradition
to sing after.
Isabela, most graceful of all the Madrigals.
You're doing great.
The most perfect flower
in this entire encanto...
No!
Will you marry...
What is happening?
Mirabel found Bruno's vision. She's in it.
She's gonna destroy the magic and now,
we're all doomed!
Abuela, please!
There's gotta be an explanation.
I hate you!
- I'm a loser!
- Luisa!
What did you do?
I'm not doing anything!
It's Bruno's vision!
The magic is strong! Everything is fine!
We are the Madrigals!
Mirabel!
Hey!
It's okay, mami.
Deep breath in, deep breath out.
Stop!
No! No!
Help! Help...
Casita! Casita!
Help me!
You're very sweaty.
Oh, no!
- Bye.
- What?
No.
Hold on!
Wait! Wait!
Why did you take the vision?
Knock, knock, knock, knock, knock.
Knock on wood.
What does it mean?
Is it why you came back or...?
Tío Bruno?
Knock, knock, knock, knock, knock.
Knock on wood.
You were never supposed to see that vision.
No one was.
- But...
- A little salt.
Sugar.
Wait.
Have you been in here patching the cracks?
Oh, that? No, no, no.
I'm too scared to go near those things.
All the patching's done by Hernando.
- Who is Hernando?
- I'm Hernando and I'm scared of nothing!
It's actually me.
I used to say my real Gift was "acting."
I'm Jorge. I make the spackle.
How long have you been back here?
You never left.
Well, I left my tower, which was,
you know, a lot of stairs...
and here, kitchen adjacent.
Plus, free entertainment.
So, what do you like?
You like sports?
Game shows?
Telenovelas?
Their love could never be.
I don't understand.
Well, because she's his aunt
and she has amnesia...
so she can't remember that she's his aunt.
It's like a very forbidden kind of...
I don't understand why you left,
but didn't leave.
Oh, well, because, the mountains
around the encanto are pretty tall.
And like I said, free food and everything.
You guys love the free food, don't ya?
Always hungry.
Never satisfied.
My Gift wasn't helping the family...
but, I love my family, you know?
I just don't know how to...
Well, anyway,
I think you should go, because...
I don't really have a good reason,
but, if I did, you'd be like...
"I should go, because that's a good reason."
Why was I in your vision?
Tío Bruno?
I just wanted to make the family proud of me.
Just once.
But if I should stop...
if I'm hurting my family...
just tell me.
I can't tell you...
because I don't know.
I had this vision the night
that you didn't get your Gift.
Abuela worried about the magic.
So, she begged me to look into the future.
See what it meant.
And I saw the magic in danger.
Our house breaking.
And then, and then, and then, I saw you.
But the vision was different.
It would change.
And there was no one answer.
No clear fate.
Like your future was undecided.
But I knew how it was gonna look.
I knew what everyone would think...
because I'm Bruno
and everyone always assumes the worst, so...
so...
You left to protect me?
I don't know which way it'll go...
but my guess...
the family, the encanto...
and the fate of the miracle itself...
Well, it's all gonna come down to you.
Or maybe I'm wrong.
You know, it's a mystery.
That's why this vision is...
Look, if I could help anymore, I would...
but that's all I know.
Good luck.
I wish I could've seen more.
Yeah.
You wish you could have seen more,
so see more!
Have another vision.
No, no.
See, I don't do visions anymore.
- But you could.
- But I won't.
You can't say the weight of the world
is on your shoulders. The end.
If our fate's up to me,
me says have another vision.
Maybe it'll show me what to do.
Look, even if I wanted to, which I don't,
you wrecked my vision cave.
Which is a problem,
'cause I need a big open space.
- We'll find one.
- Where?
Use my room.
The rats told me everything.
Don't eat those.
Our family needs help,
and you need to get outta here.
You should have told me
the second you saw the vision.
Think of the family.
I was thinking of my daughter.
Pepa, calm down.
- I'm doing my best.
- Yes.
You're lucky it's not a hurricane.
Mamá, you've always been
too hard on Mirabel.
Look around.
We must protect our family, our e ncanto.
We cannot lose our home.
People in town are becoming anxious
about the magic.
They want to see you.
Mirabel was in that vision for a reason.
Find her.
We might wanna hurry.
You can't hurry the future.
What if I show you something worse?
If I see something that you don't like,
you're gonna be all...
"Bruno makes bad things happen. Oh, he's
creepy and his vision killed my goldfish."
I don't think you make bad things happen.
Sometimes family weirdos
just get a bad rap.
You can do this.
For the nerves.
I can do this. I can do this,
I can do this, I can do this.
You might wanna hang on.
It's just the same thing.
I gotta stop!
No. I need to know which way it goes.
There's gotta be an answer.
Something we're not seeing!
You're looking at the same thing that I am.
- If there was something else...
- There!
Over there!
Butterfly!
Follow the butterfly!
Where is that?
It's all out of order.
It's the candle.
The candle's getting brighter!
- I think you're gonna help the candle!
- How?
There's someone with you.
- And you fight her!
- What?
Wait, no, no.
Is that a hug?
Am I fighting or hugging?
An embrace.
An embrace!
To make the candle bright
you have to embrace her.
Embrace who?
Almost there.
- Who is it?
- Almost there.
I got it!
Isabela?
Your sister? That's great!
Every time.
Why would embracing Isabela
do anything?
I don't know. Our family got a miracle.
How do you help a family miracle?
You hug a sister.
Mirabel?
Well, I think we're running out of time here.
It's not gonna work.
She won't hug me ever, okay?
She hates me!
Also, I don't know if you heard,
I ruined her proposal!
- Plus, P.S., she is just annoying.
- Mirabel?
- Of course it's Isabela!
What's her problem with me anyway?
She's the one with roses
coming out of her...
Mirabel!
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
You see, you're missing the point.
The fate of the family,
it's not up to her.
It's up to you.
You're exactly what this family needs.
You just have to see it.
By yourself, after I leave.
What, you're not coming?
It was your vision, Mirabel. Not mine.
You're afraid Abuela will see you.
Yep. I mean, yes, that too.
Hey, after you save the miracle, come visit.
After I save the miracle,
I'm bringing you home.
Knock, knock, knock, knock, knock.
Knock on wood.
You got this.
Just gonna save the miracle.
With a hug.
Isa? Hey.
I know we've had our issues...
but I'm ready to be a better sister...
to you.
So, we should just hug.
Let's hug it out, huh?
"Hug it out"?
Luisa can't lift an empanada...
Mariano's nose
looks like a smashed papaya!
Have you lost your mind?
Isa, I feel like you're upset.
And you know what cures being upset?
A warm embrace.
Get out.
Everything was perfect.
Abuela was happy. The family was happy.
You wanna be a better sister?
Apologize for ruining my life.
Go on.
Apologize.
I...
am...
sorry...
- that your life is so great!
- Out.
Wait!
Fine! I apologize!
I wasn't trying to ruin your life!
Some of us have bigger problems...
you selfish, entitled princess!
"Selfish"?
I've been stuck being perfect
my whole entire life!
And literally, the only thing you have ever
done for me is mess things up!
Nothing is messed up!
You can still marry that big dumb hunk!
I never wanted to marry him!
I was doing it for the family!
Oh, my gosh.
Isa...
that is a very serious confession.
Okay, get over here.
Bring it in.
Isa?
I just made something unexpected
Something sharp Something new
Isa? This is the part where we...
It's not symmetrical or perfect
But it's beautiful
And it's mine
What else can I do?
Wait Bring it in, bring it in
-Good talk, bring it in, bring it in
-What else can I do?
Let's hug
Bring it in, bring it in
Free hugs
I grow rows and rows of roses
Flor de mayo by the mile
I make perfect, practiced poses
So much hides behind my smile
What could I do if I just grew
What I was feeling in the moment?
Do you know where you're going?
What could I do if I just knew
It didn't need to be perfect?
It just needed to be
And they let me be
A hurricane of jacarandás
-Strangling figs, hanging vines
-Fig!
This is fine
Palma de cera fills the air
As I climb and I push through
What else can I do?
Can I deliver us a river of sundew?
Careful, it's carnivorous
A little just won't do
I wanna feel the shiver of something new
I'm so sick of pretty
I want something true, don't you?
You just seemed like your life's been a dream
Since the moment you opened your eyes
How far do these roots go down?
All I know are the blossoms you grow
But it's awesome to see how
You rise
- How far can I rise?
- How far can you rise?
Through the roof to the skies
Let's go
A hurricane of jacarandás
-Strangling figs
-Go
-Hanging vines
-Grow
Palma de cera fills the air
As I climb and I push through
What else?
What can you do when you are
Deeply madly truly in the moment?
Seize the moment Keep going
What can you do when you know
Who you want to be isn't perfect?
-But I'll still be okay
-Hey, everybody clear the way
-I'm coming through with tabebuia
-Tabebuia
-Making waves
-Changing minds
-You've changed mine
The way is clearer 'cause you're here
And well, I owe this all to you
What else can I do?
Show them what you can do
- What else can I do?
- There's nothing you can't do
What else can I do?
You're a bad influence.
What is going on?
Abuela? It's okay! Everything's...
We're gonna save the miracle.
The magic...
What are you talking about?
Look at our home! Look at your sister!
Please just...
Isabela wasn't happy.
Of course she isn't happy.
You ruined her proposal.
No, no, no.
She needed me to ruin her proposal.
And then we did all this!
And the candle burned brighter
and the cracks...
- Mirabel.
- That's why I'm in the vision!
I'm saving the miracle!
You have to stop, Mirabel!
The cracks started with you.
Bruno left because of you.
Luisa's losing her powers.
Isabela's out of control.
Because of you!
I don't know why you weren't given a Gift...
but it is not an excuse
for you to hurt this family.
I will never be good enough for you.
Will I?
No matter how hard I try.
No matter how hard any of us tries.
Luisa will never be strong enough.
Isabela won't be perfect enough.
Bruno left our family because
you only saw the worst in him.
Bruno didn't care about this family.
He loves this family.
I love this family.
We all love this family.
You're the one that doesn't care.
- You're the one breaking our home.
- Don't you ever...
The miracle is dying, because of you.
No, no, no!
The candle!
Casita! Get me up there!
No!
Careful, Antonio!
We gotta get out of here!
Mirabel! Mirabel!
Mirabel, we have to get out!
- Mirabel!
Mirabel, leave it!
Mirabel! The house is going to fall!
- Mirabel, get out!
- Mirabel!
No.
Mirabel!
Mirabel, are you hurt?
Julieta, come quick!
Julieta!
Don't move.
I'll be right back.
How did this happen?
Here, let me help you.
Let me help you.
- Everyone okay?
- Antonio, don't cry, papito.
How is this possible? The encanto's broken.
What do we do now?
My powers. They're gone.
What about Antonio?
What is he gonna do?
Mirabel?
Mirabel!
Where's Mirabel?
Where is she?
Mirabel!
Mirabel?
They haven't found her yet?
- Mirabel!
Mirabel!
Mirabel.
I'm sorry.
I didn't want to hurt us.
I just wanted...
to be something I'm not.
I've never been able to come back here.
This river is where we were given
our miracle.
Where Abuelo Pedro...
I thought we would have a different life.
I thought I would be a different woman.
I was given a miracle.
A second chance.
And I was so afraid to lose it...
that I lost sight of who our miracle was for.
And I am so sorry.
You never hurt our family, Mirabel.
We are broken...
because of me.
Abuela.
I can finally see.
You lost your home.
Lost everything.
You suffered so much...
all alone...
so it would never happen again.
We were saved because of you.
We were given a miracle,
because of you.
We are a family, because of you.
And nothing could ever be broken
that we can't fix... together.
I asked my Pedro for help.
Mirabel.
He sent me you.
She didn't do this!
I gave her a vision!
It was me!
I was, like, "Go!"
And she was, like...
She only wanted to help.
I don't care what you think of me,
but if you're too stubborn to...
Brunito.
I feel like I missed something important.
Come on.
What's happening? Where are we going?
Home.
It's her! I found her!
I found her!
She's back! She's back, she's back!
Mirabel!
Mamá.
Mi amor, I was so worried.
We couldn't find you.
There were bees everywhere.
I'll be okay.
Not if we don't have a house.
What? We don't have a house.
I can't say we don't have a house?
What is that?
Not a house.
Look at this home
We need a new foundation
It may seem hopeless
But we'll get by just fine
Look at this family
A glowing constellation
So full of stars
And everybody wants to shine
But the stars don't shine, they burn
And the constellations shift
I think it's time you learn
You're more than just your Gift
And I'm sorry I held on too tight
Just so afraid I'd lose you too
The miracle is not
Some magic that you've got
The miracle is you
Not some Gift Just you
All of you All of you
Okay so
We gonna talk about Bruno?
That's Bruno?
Yeah
There's a lot to say about Bruno
I'll start, okay
Pepa, I'm sorry about your wedding
Didn't mean to be upsetting
That wasn't a prophecy
I could just see you were sweating
And I wanted you to know
That your bro loves you so
Let it in, let it out
Let it rain, let it snow
Let it go
That's what I'm always saying, bro
I got a lot of apologies I got to say
Hey, we're just happy that you're here, okay?
-Come into the light
-That trip was only a night
And no matter what happens
We're gonna find our way
Yo, I knew he never left
I heard him every day
What's that sound?
I think it's everyone in town
Hey
Lay down your load
Roll me down the road
We have no Gifts But we are many
And we'll do anything for you
It's a dream when we work as a team
You're so strong
-Yeah, but sometimes I cry
-So do I
I may not be as strong
But I'm getting wiser
Yeah, I need sunlight and fertilizer
Come on
Let's plant something new and watch it fly
Straight up to the sky
Let's go
The stars don't shine, they burn
The constellations glow
The seasons change in turn
Would you watch our little girl go
She takes after you
Hey, Mariano Why so blue?
I just have so much love inside
You know, I've got this cousin too
Have you met Dolores?
Okay, I'll take it from here.
Goodbye!
You talk so loud
You take care of your mother
And you make her proud
You write your own poetry
Every night when you go to sleep
And I'm seizing the moment
So would you wake up and notice me
Dolores, I see you.
And I hear you.
Yes!
All of you All of you
- Let's get married.
- Slow down.
All of you All of you
Home sweet home
I like the new foundation
It isn't perfect
-Neither are we
-That's true
Just one more thing before the celebration
- What?
- We need a doorknob
We made this one for you.
We see how bright you burn
We see how brave you've been
Now see yourself in turn
You're the real Gift, kid
Let us in
Open your eyes
What do you see?
I see... me.
All of me
Come on! Get in here!
Yeah!
Yeah, amor!
Everyone, together...
La Familia Madrigal!